<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>开源 on 繠驖瓕III 文章展示</title>
    <link>https://rtx3.com/term/%E5%BC%80%E6%BA%90/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 开源 on 繠驖瓕III 文章展示</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rtx3.com/term/%E5%BC%80%E6%BA%90/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>统一登录开源服务安装</title>
      <link>https://rtx3.com/post/casdoor-installation-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rtx3.com/post/casdoor-installation-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;统一登录开源服务casdoor部署&#34;&gt;统一登录开源服务Casdoor部署&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;统一登录是自动运维的基础以及基石，它可以极大的减少用户的管理成本。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;常用的统一登录方式有&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AD&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LDAP&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CAS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;OAUTH&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;开源服务提供了大部分的接入方式，并且依赖简单，值得使用。&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;当使用在生产环境时，需使用K8S等方式实现高可用。&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;！当使用在生产环境时，将管理人员使用的登录服务与普通用户使用的登录服务隔离。&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;casdoor-features&#34;&gt;Casdoor features&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Casdoor follows a front-end and back-end separate architecture, developed by Golang. It supports high concurrency, provides a web-based UI for management, and supports localization in 10+ languages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Casdoor supports third-party application login, such as GitHub, Google, QQ, and WeChat, and it supports extending third-party login with plugins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Casdoor supports authorization management based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://casbin.org/&#34;&gt;Casbin&lt;/a&gt;. It supports ACL, RBAC, ABAC, and RESTful access control models.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Casdoor provides phone verification code, email verification code, and password retrieval functions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Casdoor supports auditing and recording of accessing logs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Casdoor integrates with Alibaba Cloud, Tencent Cloud, and Qiniu Cloud image CDN cloud storage.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Casdoor allows customization of registration, login, and password retrieval pages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Casdoor supports integration with existing systems by database synchronization, enabling smooth transition to Casdoor.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Casdoor supports mainstream databases such as MySQL, PostgreSQL, and SQL Server, and it supports the extension of new databases with plugins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-casdoor-works&#34;&gt;How Casdoor Works&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Casdoor follows the authorization process built upon the OAuth 2.0 protocol. It is highly recommended to have a brief understanding of how OAuth 2.0 works. You can refer to this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/an-introduction-to-oauth-2&#34;&gt;introduction&lt;/a&gt; to OAuth 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
